So now we're looking at the front side top bottom planes of each feature.
Start with the around the face, jawline first.
I'm thinking this is just probably a bit too light.
This area, well actually I went for something round there.
So it kind of matches Bonnie's dark in this shape up here.
So first, I'm going to put something round here.
I'll put this shape in for that.
And then I'm going to pick out these darker shapes after.
So it's going to be the Lizarin.
So we'll probably have to go slightly darker than what we think in there.
Some yellow, green.
A bit too dark.
Some middle Lizarin.
Lighter green.
Just a bit too orangey.
Still darker I think.
Yellow in there.
Give it some depth.
Something round that.
Something round there.
Maybe need to darken this shape up as well.
Some pure Lizarin.
Green.
Yellow for depth.
Looking too grey.
Yeah, something like that.
A bit darker.
Going over some of these.
Transition.
Okay.
Can go a bit slightly darker.
In that shape.
That shape there.
Okay.
So there.
A bit darker shape.
More red.
I'll put this chin shape.
Sorry, underneath the cheek shape.
So it comes around.
Decide a bit more green.
In there.
Okay.
I'll take this down here.
Soften that edge.
Okay.
Soften this edge.
Okay, this was probably a bit more.
A bit more yellow in there.
Red shape.
Something round that.
Okay, middle Lizarin.
A bit more yellow.
Okay.
So then just looking at this temple.
Just looks a bit too green.
Going to add a bit more warmth into that.
Okay.
Then slightly darker on the temple.
Plenty more red.
A bit darker in there.
Okay, then the Zygomatic arch.
That's a bit lighter.
Okay.
Soften this edge.
Now it's a bit more.
It's a bit more pink in there.
Forehead.
Sorry.
A bit more pink in there.
Okay, so I'm going to look at the front side planes.
Starting with the leading eye.
Look at the brow.
Just going to start with the brow.
Going to look at this shape here.
You've got this little shape in there.
It gets slightly darker.
A bit of that violet in there.
And that orange red.
Maybe.
Same on the inside.
Like a violet orange red.
Inside of the eye there.
A bit darker.
Okay.
What's my shadow shape?
I'm going to bring that back.
A bit of violet.
A bit of orange.
Maybe more orange.
More orange.
Just the left side.
A bit too dark now.
Lighten that a bit.
Maybe some orange.
Okay, so we've got the brow across the top here.
Then here it gets slightly darker.
Across here it is slightly on the green side.
Lighten that.
More green.
More yellow.
Lighten up.
Lighter.
Kind of from this side here.
Then it gets slightly darker.
Brow.
Darken green red.
Darker.
On the green side.
There's quite a bit of red in there.
This is quite kind of soft.
The line of the brow.
Getting from the plane.
The eye.
That's a bit more kind of neutral.
Something around this.
It's on here.
A bit of yellow in there.
Just a bit too flat.
More yellow.
Some green.
Push that brow up a bit more.
It looks like the front plane.
The eye.
No shape.
The front.
Top and side.
Just going to indicate the...
This underside.
Okay, so I've got the...
This underside of the brow.
So I'm not looking at the accents.
Alizarin.
Orange touch of green.
On the alizarin side.
Okay.
Then...
Side plane of the lid.
It's going to be a bit darker.
So...
A bit more red in there.
The plane.
The side plane a bit more neutral.
A bit more green.
And the top plane.
A bit lighter.
A bit more on the alizarin side.
Okay.
A bit more alizarin.
A bit cooler.
Up here.
Okay.
On the side of the eye.
Same thing.
We can use this.
Alizarin.
Okay.
Well, look at the...
Wine to the eye first.
Okay.
So the...
Wine to the eye.
Almost a...
Violet.
Same blue.
Touch of orange.
Darker.
Again.
Okay.
This eye is a bit more...
A bit lighter.
A bit more neutral.
A bit more on the...
See alizarin.
Touch of orange in there.
Okay.
Touch of...
Wine to the eye on this side.
That goes into the tea dot.
So that tea dot is...
Slightly more on the...
The red side.
Lightly darker.
Okay.
We've got this shadow.
Corner of the eye.
Just more on the kind of red side.
Touch of orange.
Violet.
Touch more red.
That corner.
That's going to put the whole thing in.
You can fix stuff out afterwards.
Shape when it comes down a bit further.
Okay.
Bring in that...
A bit of shape back there.
Okay.
Just losing the...
Eye shape.
Bring that back.
Then we've got the underside of the eye.
A bit darker.
It turns away.
Green.
Okay.
So...
Some say yellow-green.
Mix that with the red.
Alizarin.
The underside of the eye.
Darker.
There.
Pick out the top plane.
Put them on the alizarin side.
A bit cooler.
Supply alizarin.
The underside of the eye.
Look at this.
Shape.
Slightly darker there.
Then we can say slightly lighter here.
And then lighter again.
I'm going to put in that little triangle there.
Okay.
It's a quite kind of...
Alizarin-y.
That eye turns in.
Quite bright.
Okay.
A bit darker.
Maybe.
Okay.
It's a bit lighter.
Sliding that lighter in a bit.
Okay.
I'm going to take that up into the corner.
Then you've got that cheek.
It's kind of a yellow-y green.
Take this round there a bit.
Use that edge.
Okay.
Sock it.
The other eye now.
Okay.
So I've got the brow.
So I'm going to make the brow...
slightly lighter.
A bit of yellow in there.
A bit of lighter yellow.
I'm just going to lighten that.
Round there a bit.
More yellow.
You've got the brow.
It turns into the shadow.
It gets a bit warmer.
It's a bit more...
That violet.
It's a bit warmer in there.
I should...
Just in.
Get some...
Touch of red.
In there.
Okay.
The eye.
Just under the...
The...
Just under here.
I'm going to make it slightly darker.
Because it turns away.
That was the...
The yellow-y green.
Mix.
Yellow.
Much yellow.
Okay.
It turns under.
Then...
I'm going to make it into this...
This ring shape in there.
I'm just going to pick out that light shape.
That's going to be some...
Lighter lizard.
Probably...
Something around here.
Maybe make it a bit darker.
Greenish side in there.
A bit lighter.
Then looking at the underside.
I actually need to pull that...
Eye up.
It's going to lift everything.
So all this is going to need to raise up.
Yellow.
Red touch of burnt umber.
Maybe...
Keeping that eye out with the...
Real shape.
Okay.
Need to bring that eye shape back.
Now I can pick out the...
White of the eye.
What kind of blue in there?
So some blue.
Some red in there.
Then we've got the underside of the...
Lids.
That's kind of a bit more...
See, there's a bit of orange in there.
Quite kind of bright.
Darker than that.
Which is green, just to take that down a bit.
The eye turns away.
It's going to get slightly darker.
A bit of green in there.
Okay.
A bit of Israeli.
It's not a plane of that eye.
I'm going to get this...
Bottom plane right.
Keeping around that.
Then the brow.
It's slightly darker.
A bit more violet.
Orange.
Just around there.
It's not darker.
Okay, let's look at the nose.
Side plane.
Side plane of the nose.
It's going to be slightly darker than the front plane.
Okay.
Bottom plane.
The nose.
The brow of the brow.
So that is dark enough.
Okay, so maybe I just need to pick out the...
Bottom plane.
And the front plane.
Okay, so the bottom plane.
Okay, something around that.
A bit kind of orangey.
And the side plane.
It's going to be a bit darker.
Okay, some alizarin.
Put some yellow in there.
Touch green.
Check that.
Darker.
Let me tone that down.
Take the round that.
Okay, so maybe a bit...
Maybe a bit of light on that front plane.
Okay.
Some more orange.
Orange to alizarin.
So yellow.
Or yellow to alizarin.
Side plane.
It's slightly cooler.
The nose turns away.
Okay.
This has the nose.
Have a look at the mouth.
It's a bit of a filter.
It's slightly darker.
Then...
It's muzzle shape.
Shipping here.
Slightly more on the pink side.
Okay.
So look at the muzzle.
Maybe some of this light stuff.
With green.
Warmer.
Green.
A bit of yellow.
Darker.
Okay.
And the muzzle's side.
That's a bit more on the green side.
So yellow.
Green.
Some alizarin.
One green.
With some alizarin.
Touch more alizarin.
Okay.
Then there's a bit more on the pink side.
Let's go up into the cheek.
Slightly darker.
A bit more pink.
More alizarin.
Darker.
Yellow.
Darker mean.
Okay.
Muscle.
Then...
Got the other side of the lip.
Okay.
I think there's a bit more red overall.
Red orange.
Alizarin.
Yellow.
And this.
Warm this up a bit more.
Okay.
So I'm just going to pick out...
Blend the chin.
It's like a parallelogram shape here.
Slightly more on the alizarin side.
A bit of yellow in there.
Okay.
Then the chin.
A bit more yellow.
Alizarin.
There.
And the plain on the chin.
Okay.
Then...
That's a little bit of furrow.
It's going to make that slightly darker.
More red.
Some green.
Okay.
It's like a side plane.
And for the lips.
Okay.
So we're going to go...
Go this.
Front plane of the lips.
Slightly darker.
Then you've got your side plane.
Got the side plane.
Got that side plane.
Looks pretty slightly lighter.
Just capture the light.
Then the...
So they're almost the same.
Okay.
So let's look at the front plane.
The lip.
Slightly more red.
Alizarin.
Maybe take it down.
New green.
Okay.
Front plane.
Top plane.
Your side plane.
It's going to be slightly lighter.
Just call that the side plane.
Then the front plane.
Then like that.
Then as the lip turns away.
The back.
A bit cooler.
Bit of violet.
Okay.
So let's look at the ear.
I'm just going to group.
All these shapes.
Look at the...
Okay.
So look at this shape here.
The shallow shape.
I'm going to put that in.
Then we'll pick out that light shape after.
Okay.
I'm just going to call that.
So that bit's some alizarin.
Quite dark.
All that.
I'll wash the brush out.
It's working with wet paint.
All the alizarin.
Say green.
Some yellow.
Okay.
We've got something like that.
It's not quite dark enough.
Okay.
Let's go that little shape.
Let's put out a bit more alizarin.
Bring this shadow back around.
Okay.
So we've got this inside edge of the conch.
We'll make this...
Look at this shape here.
Make this slightly darker.
Yeah.
It's a green.
The shape in here.
Lost my...
Then we've got the inside of the conch shape.
It's kind of...
Alizarin-y.
Orange-y.
Touch green.
Okay.
All that mixed there.
Just on the inside of here.
Inside edge of the conch.
Then looking at this shape here.
All this gets slightly darker.
Around there.
Around where the air tends down.
Touch more green to that to neutralise that.
Maybe.
Back into that shadow.
Back in that a bit more.
Okay.
So I'm going to leave that there.
Call that the front and side planes.
Okay.
So I've got a few edges.
That cheek.
Something that edge.
Something this edge round here.
Okay.
So I'm going to say that's it for the front and side planes.
Almost.
So I'm going to say that's it.
All right.
I'm just going to leave that there.
A couple of quick fixes.
This edge of the chin.
Okay.
So that's that.
Front sides.